Welcome to our new Line Chain Academy course, Building Amid Agents with Line Graph.
Chat is a familiar user interaction pattern for agents, where user request something of an agent,
an agent can call various tools, and respond to the user with an output.
But there are a lot of tasks for which chat isn't quite appropriate.
As an example, many users don't want to actually tell an agent do something.
They want an agent to listen passively to certain events and respond to them automatically.
Many times we don't want agents to only handle one request at a time.
We may want agents to handle many events concurrently.
Sometimes we want agents to do work in the background for us,
and only notify us at specific points, like when the work has been done,
when they need clarification on something, or when they want to notify us about something.
And finally, with chat, you typically want the agent to work quickly.
But if agents are doing work in the background, it can take much longer.
A user isn't waiting around. They're only notified by the agent when appropriate.
So this collection of attributes is what we call ambient agents.
Now in this course, we're going to build an ambient agent that can handle email,
which is a great example of the kind of task you may want agents like this to take on.
It's going to build an agent that can effectively manage your email inbox.
It will ingest incoming emails and perform actions like draft responses or schedule meetings.
Now because these are sensitive tasks, we're going to show how to use human loop to approve certain agent actions.
And importantly, we're also going to introduce memory so that the agent learns from our feedback over time.
And by the end of this course, you're going to understand all these components
and how they can be used generally to build agents, not just that handle email,
but they can handle many different types of tasks.
So how can we actually build this?
Let's take the simplest possible email system.
For every incoming email, the assistant produces a response email.
Now the assistant can send that response using tool calling,
which I'll talk about briefly in a minute.
And if you think about the system in terms of agency versus predictability,
where agency is the ability for the system to make different decisions and predictability is,
simply the predictability decisions the system makes,
this would be low agency but high predictability.
It will always call a tool to send off an email for every incoming email that it receives.
The central concept underpinning this system and agents more broadly is tool calling.
Let's imagine we had an email API.
This could be the Gmail API as an example.
We can turn that into a tool and bind it to an LLM.
When we do that binding process, the LLM understands the arguments necessary to actually call that tool.
So when it receives a request,
it reasons about the request and can make a decision to call the tool,
but importantly produces a structured output,
which contains the arguments that the tool actually needs.
Independently, then, the tool can be executed with those arguments in order to,
in this case, send off an email.
Now it's important to note that a simple system to always call an email tool is pretty limited.
What if we don't want to respond?
So there's many different ways people have found to effectively lay out workflows.
This is just LLM calls within predefined code paths.
That can instrument specific logic.
Here's an example where we're put a router prior to that send email tool call.
This router then makes decision about whether or not we're going to send the email.
If we make a decision to send, we'll then go ahead and proceed to what we just talked about,
an LLM with access to an email tool and the email sent.
Now if you think about this system, we've bump up the agency a little bit.
Now it has the ability to make a decision.
It can decide whether or not to respond.
And in turn, it's a little bit less predictable.
We don't quite know what I'll decide given it an incoming email.
Now let's push this even further.
Imagine we took that LLM and instead of giving it a single tool right email,
we give it a collection of different tools.
And every time it called a tool, we just returned the output of that tool call back to the LLM.
We'll let the LLM think about what was performed and decide what to do next.
We let that proceed in a loop until some termination condition.
This very simply is an agent.
And as noted, the agency is quite a bit higher than the other two.
And one way to visualize that is with the initial system,
for every incoming email, it made a single decision to write a response and send it.
The agent in contrast can choose any sequence of tool calls given the tools it has access to.
So in this case, let's say it had access to three tools.
Check calendar schedule meeting, write an email.
It can pick any sequence.
It wants based upon the email input.
Now a very important question is how to think about workflows or his agents.
Typically, a good statistic is if you can easily draw the control flow on a whiteboard
and it's very easy to numerate in advanced workflows appropriate,
and often is lower latency and cost than an agent.
But if you actually need more flexible decision making,
and you can't quite know until runtime,
or in this case, until you receive an email,
how you want to respond in terms of tool calls,
then an agent is more appropriate.
And it's okay to trade off greater reasoning for higher latency and potentially higher cost.
Now, line graph comes in because it's a framework of low-level components
that lets you flexibly build and combine workflows and agents.
Line graph is composed of nodes and edges where nodes are just units of work.
There's Python functions or TypeScript code that you control explicitly.
So you'll just write those functions as you'll see shortly.
And everything happens with the node you have complete control over.
Now, edges are just transitions between nodes,
which are going to lay out in advance as you build your workflow arrangement.
This will dictate the control flow of the application.
Now, one benefit of line graph is that because it uses very low-level components,
just simply nodes and edges, you can build many different workflows as well as agents very easily.
It allows you to kind of move to where you want to sit along this curve.
You can build systems that are strictly agents.
You can build workflows.
You can combine agents and workflows together.
Now, one of the things we built into line graph that we found to be very important,
in particular, as we'll see here, building an ambient agent,
is a persistence layer that enables human and loop and long-term memory.
As we'll see, it's important in many cases that agents can pause in a way human feedback.
And that's what the persistence layer affords this.
Not only that, it also gives us long-term memory.
The central idea behind persistence is that you have check pointing.
So, as you'll see, when you lay out your graph as a set of nodes,
the check pointer will save the state of the application.
And if we pause it, that state is available for us to resume from later.
Line graph also comes built with an interactive development environment,
Line Graph Studio, which you're going to see extensively throughout this course.
And it provides an easy on-roam to deployment.
And you'll see that we can very easily go from code running in a notebook
to a deployable application.
Before I actually build in our agent,
I want to make sure we understand the fundamentals of Line Graph very clearly
and how it works with Langshin and Langsmith.
Here's a general schematic where you can see the three together.
Langshin provides many integrations that we'll be using, particularly chat models,
and some very useful methods for binding tools or structured outputs.
Line Graph will be using for agent orchestration.
Langsmith remusing for observability, like tracing, as well as evaluation.
And as you'll see, these three all play really nicely together,
but this is how they're related.
Now, chat models are the foundation of LLM applications.
They're typically accessed through a chat interface,
which takes the list of messages input,
the returns and messages output,
and Langshin's standard interface for chat models called init chat model,
where you can just simply pass the name of your provider and model,
as well as any parameters that you want to use.
Now, Langshin has some universal methods
for accessing chat models.
Invoke just passes a single input to the chat model and returns an output.
In this case, we can just pass a string and under the hood,
it's converted into a chat message and sent in for us.
We can see we get a message out.
Now, here's the message, and you can see it has this content,
as well as response metadata.
Now, tools, as mentioned previously,
are utilities that can be called by chat models.
We can very easily create tools in Langshin
from Python functions as an example using this tool decorator.
Now, this function is a tool,
and when we do this, the tool arguments, as well as description,
are automatically inferred.
These are things that are going to be passed to the model,
so the model knows what this particular tool is expecting.
Now, one thing that's very nice is that
the chat model interface in Langshin
provides some common methods for working with tools.
In particular, this bind tools method,
we can simply pass a list of tools in some useful parameters.
So this tool choice parameter means that the model is enforced
to call any available tool that it has.
So it will always have to call a tool.
Parallel tool calls simply enforces the model calls a single tool at a time.
Sometimes models can actually make multiple tool calls at once,
and we can control that.
So we define our model with tools.
We invoke it just like before.
In this case, we invoke it with a message that's related to the tool it has,
and we can see the tool call itself has the arguments needed
to actually run the tool to subject content.
We can pass those args directly to our tool right email and just run it,
and then we can see our tool was executed.
So this is a very important concept to understand.
You can bind tools to LLMs.
LLMs can call tools.
Calling tools simply means that LLMs produce a structured output of arguments
necessary to actually run the tool,
and then the tool can be independently run.
This is really the foundational component for building agents.
And what we see above illustrates this simple flow that we saw before.
We bind a single send email tool to an LLMs,
and enforce it to call that tool when responding to incoming emails or requests.
Now as discussed, workflows and agents really extend from this.
In case of workflows, we can embed LLMs calls in predefined code paths.
As we see here, with a router prior to our LLMs calls our email tool.
Agents just extend this a bit further,
allowing LLMs to sequentially call tools in a loop.
Now, land graph sits underneath any workflow or agent,
and it provides a few specific benefits we're going to walk through now in code in some simple examples.
The first benefit is control.
It makes it very easy to define or combine ages and workflows.
The second benefit is persistence.
It provides a way to persist the state of our graph,
which enables both memory and human loop, which we're going to see.
And it provides an easy on-ramp for testing debugging and deploying applications.
Now let's talk about control first.
Land graph lets you define your applications a graph,
with three important things that you just specify.
The state or the information you want to track over the course of the application,
nodes, how do you want to update the state over the course of the application,
and edges, how do you want to connect the nodes together.
Now we use the state graph class to initialize a line graph graph,
and we just pass in a state object.
Now the state object is basically the schema for the information we want to track over the course of the application.
Now there's a few options for defining your schema.
As an example, type dicts are fast,
but they don't support default values.
Data classes are actually quite nice because they do support defaults.
Padantic is a bit slower, but allows for type validation.
So you can choose the schema that's appropriate for your application.
In this simple case, let's just use the type dict.
You can see I'm defining my state schema here.
It just has two keys, request, and email both strings.
I then initialize my state graph with my schema.
Now let's take what we did previously.
We call our model of tools with an input request.
We get the arguments, and we call it tool.
We can put that all in a node in our graph,
and you'll see two interesting things about this.
One, the node takes in our state object.
Remember, we define that above a natural sedictionary.
From the dictionary, we can extract any keys we want and utilize them.
Now the second thing is, it returns a dict.
This return is basically updating our state.
Now by default, when we return from a node,
it overwrites that particular key in our state,
but when we define our state object,
there are ways to customize it to do different things,
like appending, and we'll talk about that shortly.
In this simple case, though, we're going to call our model of tools.
It's going to produce a tool call.
We then pass those arguments to our right email tool.
We can email out, and we'll update or overwrite our state key email with that output.
Now we can specify the control flow by adding nodes and edges to our graph.
We'll add our single node, right email node,
and two edges to start, go to that node,
from that node, go to end, and finally, we compile it.
When we've done these things, we can very easily then run our graph
just by calling invoke, and we can pass an initial value to our state.
In this case, we'll initialize our graph with request,
and we see the output of the tool call is written to email in our state.
The state dict is just returned.
We run our graph.
Now in the above case, we very simply used edges to start,
go to our single node, and then go from our single node to end.
We can also do conditional routing using conditional edges.
Let me show an example of that.
Now let's split our graph up into two different nodes, call the LLM,
and run our tool.
Now we can add a conditional edge.
It looks to see if a tool call was made by call alone,
and if so, run the tool if not to send.
This is a very common thing that we do when we build agents.
We use conditional routing as a termination condition.
If the agent is making a tool call, we run it.
If not, we end and exit the agent loop.
This is a very useful thing to be aware of.
Now let's see something else that's interesting.
This time, I initialize my graph with messages state.
This is a prebuilt state object in line graph.
That is a single key messages.
And when we update it, as you see here,
it just simply depends to that list of messages
as opposed to overwriting.
Now this is also very useful when you're building agents
because you want to basically accumulate messages
over the course of the agent's tool calling trajectory.
And you'll see in this should continue edge.
All we do is we get the last message
from the list of messages.
We check if it's a tool call.
And if so, we return the name of the next node to go to run tool.
Otherwise, we end.
So you'll see an interesting difference.
With conditional edges,
you return the name of the next node you want to visit.
But with nodes,
you return updates to your state.
So we'll compile this and show the graph.
So now we start, we call our model.
And depending upon whether the model likes a tool call,
we'll run the tool or not.
Let's go ahead and try that out.
And there we go.
We pass our input message.
Our model makes a tool call.
We then route to the run tool node.
And the tool is run as we see here.
Now with just these local components,
you can build a lot of different things.
Now because agents are so common,
we have a pre-built abstraction for it,
which I show right here called create react agent.
Now to this, agent abstraction,
we just pass our model, our list of tools,
and a system prompt.
We run the agent just like before,
passing in messages.
And we can see that the model in this case makes a tool call.
The tool is run.
Now here's the little difference
relative that we saw before.
Remember before after tools run we just end.
With the agent though as discussed,
tool calls are returned back to the LLM.
So what happens is,
the model then sees that tool call
and provides us a response indicating the tools called
and does not call any further tools.
That then exits the tool calling loop
and the agent ends.
So now we've seen the basic components of LLM graph.
And we've introduced the agent abstraction to LLM graph.
Now in a very important thing when building agents
and workflows, as we're going to see a lot more later,
is the idea of persistence.
It can be very useful to allow agents
to pause during long-running tasks.
Minecraft has a built-in persistence layer
to enable this, implemented through check pointers.
Now what happens is, after every node,
the check pointer saves the state of the graph.
So if you pause your graph,
the state is saved and available
for resuming in a later point in time.
Now let's show an example of this.
I can take that same create react agent abstraction
and pass it a check pointer.
I'll ask something about good practices
for writing emails.
Now with a check pointer,
you'll see I need to now pass a thread ID.
This basically groups checkpoints together
so I can reference them later.
Our agent ran.
And what's really nice is,
we can get this current state of our agent
just by passing in the thread.
We'll call agent.getState.
And we can go ahead and extract
all the messages currently in state of our agent.
Now currently we see we just have our input
and we have the agent's response.
Now let's continue the conversation.
All I need to do is re-invoke my agent
and I'll say, hey great,
let's use lesson three,
be concise to craft a response to my boss
and I can just pass in the config.
That config indicates the thread.
If I can run, we can see the agent then
has access to the prior messages
because they're saved to the thread
and it proposes an email.
I can then follow up again
by passing in that thread ID
and say I like this.
Go ahead and write the email.
And now you can see it goes ahead,
calls the tool.
The tool is executed
and it confirms that the email has been sent.
Now another very powerful thing
that check pointing allows
is that we can interrupt our graph
at very specific points.
Here's an example of a very simple graph
where I want to interrupt
at a particular node human feedback
to collect feedback from the user.
All you do is add this interrupt object
to the node
and compile my graph with a checkpointer.
We can see our graph flow here.
We'll create a thread like before.
We'll run a graph.
Now I'll just simply stream updates
to each node as the graph is running
by indicating the stream mode updates.
Now it's interesting here
when we hit that human feedback node,
we can see the graph emits an interrupt.
With a value, please provide feedback
and that's exactly what we passed to
that interrupt object.
Now to resume,
all you need to do is use this command object
in the line graph
and pass in whatever human feedback I want.
Now to resume from the interrupt,
we just invoke our graph again
with the command object
and we pass resume.
We can simply pass a string
and our feedback gets passed through
to our node
and written to our state
as user feedback.
So whatever we pass
to this resume
and command after an interrupt
is directly passed into our graph.
And what we can see right here
is where we received that feedback,
run it to state.
Now because I set these two environment variables,
everything we just did
is logged to Langsmith.
I can then look at my Langsmith traces
for any of the above executions.
Here's an example looking at our agent
and we see here in Langsmith.
Here are graph nodes for our agent.
We can open this up.
This shows us the model call specifically.
Open that up.
And you can see here are the bound tools.
We actually called the right email tool right here.
Here is a list of messages,
the L and received.
And then here is the resulting tool call.
We then went to the tool node,
open that up,
and you can see here is the tool in vocation
and the output of our tool
as a tool message.
And finally, that went back to our agent.
We can see that call model,
node,
we can look at the L and call specifically,
see that node tools called
and a module response
with an IAM message saying
that email has been sent.
So Langsmith is very nice way to dig into your traces
and it also logs useful metadata for you
as you can see over here.
Now in addition to Langsmith,
I want to talk about another important
and useful feature in the Langtrain ecosystem
that allows us to deploy agents
or workflows very easily.
And that's called Langarth platform.
So everything we've done here in a notebook
is great for testing
and for rapid prototyping.
But what if I want to turn any of this code
into a deployable application?
That's where Langarth platform comes in.
It makes it very easy to go
from workflow agents to
a deployable server
with an API that we can use to interact with our graph.
In addition,
Langarth platform gives us
an interactive IDE called Langarth Studio.
It's a very useful way to further inspect
and debug our agent.
So to use Langarth platform,
all we need to do is ensure that our project
has a structure as shown here.
So the thing that really matters here
is this Langarth.json.
This is just a configuration file.
In the root of this repo,
this just specifies dependencies, graphs,
environment variables,
and other things needed to start
the Langarth server.
It's a pretty simple configuration.
The main thing the configuration will have
is just simply the graph names
and the path.
As an example,
in a repo,
in this directory,
we have a file called Langarth 101.py,
which contains some of the code
that we just prototyped in this notebook
as a deployable graph.
Now with Langarth platform,
there's a few different deployment options.
I want to make sure our clear.
So the simplest and free option is just local deployment
that runs on your local machine,
and all I need to do from the root of this directory
is run Langarth dev.
Now this still has persistence,
checkpoints should be written to the local file system.
Now they're also very self-hosted options for deployment,
and there's hosted deployments,
which use Postgres,
for persistence.
So we'll just run Langarth dev
from the root of our repo,
and see what happens.
So if we run Langarth dev,
you'll see this spin up in your browser.
This is Langarth Studio.
You can scroll through the various graphs
that are existence repo.
Click on Langarth 101.
This is one of the graphs we built in the notebook.
We can open up this input pane,
open up messages,
pass in a message,
submit,
and you can see the state of the graph
over here,
which shows each node in the graph,
as well as the state updates,
at that particular node.
You can also click on this open-run Langsmiths,
and look at the trace to see the LM call,
in the call LM node,
as well as the tool execution in the run tool node.
Now another nice thing I'll point out
is that you can see the API docs for your local deployment,
right here,
and you can browse through
to see all the endpoints available to you.
So we've covered many of the foundations needed
for this course.
We've covered Langchain
in some of the useful interfaces,
such as init chat model,
tools,
and using chat models.
We've talked about the basis of Langarth
and agents versus workflows.
We also showed both Langsmith,
as well as Langarth deployment
and Langarth Studio.
We covered persistence and interrupts.
We also covered Langsmith and observability,
as well as Langarth platform,
showcasing local deployments,
and Langarth Studio.
So these are really all the foundations
you're going to need for the rest of this course.