Now that we've seen the fundamentals of Langgraf, I want to review the agent itself and how we're going to approach building it over the course of this class.
We're going to build an ambient agent that can run your email. It's going to have four main components.
The first is the agent itself, which we're going to build first. You can see that in blue.
The second is actually testing it, which you see in orange.
We're going to show how to do that using Langsmith.
The third is adding human loop, and the fourth is adding memory to learn preferences over time.
Now for building the agent itself, we're going to use Langgraf as we've introduced,
and we're going to showcase how you can combine an agent and specific workflow components, notably a router, together into a functioning system.
While building this, we're going to be making use of Langgraf Studio, as you saw previously as well.
Now with this agent built, would you actually turn it on? And many people would probably say no. That's where testing comes in.
This is a survey we put out last year, asking around 400 professionals, the major challenges associated with building and productionizing agents.
Many mentioned performance, quality, cost, safety, and latency.
For these reasons, testing to benchmark the performance of our agent is going to be very important.
We'll show you to build datasets in Langsmith, we'll show how to build tests in Langsmith,
and we'll show we can use this to actually benchmark the performance of our agent.
For an agent like this is oversight over our email, the cost of error is very high.
So we're going to show how to incorporate human loop with our agent.
We'll add human loop to get particular sensitive actions, like certain tool calls.
We'll show agent inbox as a lightweight UX for this.
Our agent will simply send all notifications to inbox, or we can review, approve, or edit specific tool calls, like sending the email itself.
Based upon the feedback we give the agent in inbox, we're going to then update the agent's memory.
So it'll learn our preferences over time.
So here's a map of the various lessons.
We're going to start with building the email system.
We're then going to evaluate it using Langsmith.
We'll then add human loop and show how to use agent inbox, and finally wild memory and deploy it.
So now let's walk through the code of actually building our agent.
And to motivate it, I'm going to show you the agent working in studio.
This is what we're going to build.
I can pass in an email, run, we'll triage the email accordingly.
If triage determines that we should respond, our response agent will use its tools to respond appropriately.
We can follow, in this particular case, the input.
The triage router decides to respond to the email.
It passes the email in messages to our agent.
Our agent then decides to make a tool call to write email.
The tool call is executed.
And then we finish.
So let's dive into the code now.
And we're in this blue block right here.
So that's what we're going to build out first.
You've already seen how to define tools in Langchain.
We're going to go ahead and define a few tools that are relevant for an email system,
write email, schedule meeting, check calendar availability, and done.
Now, of course, these are just mock tools.
We're not actually hitting a real email API for the purpose of this notebook and building out our assistant.
But the repo does have the option to connect it into as an example Gmail, if you want to.
Now let's talk about the philosophy of building our assistant.
Remember, we talked about workflows in agents previously.
If we think about the control flow of our application for every incoming email,
we want to make some decision about it.
Do we respond, just notify the user or ignore it?
Because this step we always want to do first, we hard code this router as the first step in our overall assistant.
And if the router decides to respond, we then send to an agent.
Now, why do you use an agent here?
Well, for the email response task, it's a little bit more open ended.
The tools you want to call depend a bit on the content of the email itself.
As an example, sometimes you might respond directly.
Other times you might schedule a meeting.
Sometimes you might do both.
And so the email response process is a bit more open ended.
And in that case, we use an agent.
Now the nice thing is, we'll show how easy it is to compose these two things in LandGraph.
So let's build our router first.
The router handles the triage decision.
We'll define our state.
We introduced this previously.
We'll just use messages state, which is that prebuilt state object in LandGraph.
And we'll add two new keys, email input and classification decision.
So our state object in total has three keys, messages, email input and classification decision.
Now we're going to define the triage node.
I'm going to show a very simple but generally nice trick for doing things like routing using language models.
Many language models support structured outputs.
In fact, that's what's happening when we perform tool calling.
But because this is so common,
our init chat model interface has a particular method with structured output where you can pass in a schema.
The output will be coerced to adhere to that schema.
Here's an example where we pass the pedantic model with two fields, reasoning and classification.
We provide descriptions of each field.
And when we bind this schema to our model,
the model is aware of those descriptions and uses them to help coerce its output to meet this particular schema.
So what we're doing here is we're telling the model to make a classification decision,
select from these three options, ignore, respond or notify and give your reasoning.
Now as we saw previously, we can pass in the state.
This state's going to contain an email input.
We'll just use some simple utils to parse it and format some prompts that we have defined in our repo,
triaging the incoming email.
We then invoke our router with a list of messages that contains our prompts.
And this output is going to be a structured object that adheres the schema that we passed.
So we can extract the classification decision from that object.
If the classification is respond, we're going to go to the response agent.
And we're going to update our messages state with the email so that the response agent knows what to respond to.
Now if the decision is to ignore or just notify the user, we go to end and nothing happens.
In all cases, we update state with the classification decision.
Now you'll see something interesting here.
We return with this command object.
So what's happening here?
Before we talked about returning just with, for example, a dict to update our state,
command allows us to both update the state as we see here with this update,
but also decide where to go next in our graph.
So it's a way of combining state updates and control flow in a single step.
So in this case, it just saves us a little bit of time because we don't have to specify all those edges from this particular node to end or response agent.
Now here's where we'll build our agent.
Now we already have some good intuition for building agents from before,
but in this case, I'm going to try to build an agent with each node individually.
So you can kind of see what's under the hood of our create react agent abstraction.
So first we just pull in our agent prompt.
And this will just indicate the tools that the agent has available to it and our agent system prompt.
And this is where we just very simply define our instructions.
Now we'll define the node that makes our LM call.
In this case, we define the tools as a list.
We bind them to our model.
We format our prompt,
which includes tool descriptions as well as any background preferences.
Updating our messages state with the LM output.
Now we define a node called tool handler,
which will be responsible for just executing the tool.
Remember, we saw all these principles previously, so this is really nothing new.
We'll go ahead and get all the tool calls from the prior message.
We'll invoke it and we'll update our state with a tool message indicating the tool has been called.
Now here we'll add some simple conditional routing,
which basically says continue calling tools until the done tool is called.
Remember before we use the termination condition as no tool call has been executed.
In this case, a specific tool done is our termination condition.
This is just another way to set up agents with an alternative termination condition.
Now we can lay out our agent graph.
This is very simple.
We add our LM node.
We add our tool handler node.
We add our conditional edge to decide whether or not to continue based upon the tool called.
And we can see what's going to happen is the LM will run,
it will call a tool because we enforce tool calling,
and it will continue calling tools until it calls the done tool, at which point it'll exit.
Now a very nice thing about Langrath is you can easily compose different things.
Remember we previously defined our triage router.
We can add the triage router as a node to this larger workflow
and add our response agent, which we defined here, as a node.
This effectively means that the agent is a subgraph of our overall workflow.
We'll add a start edge to initiate the triage router and we'll compile our graph.
So now you can see we go to the triage router.
Depending on the decision made by the triage router,
we may go to the response agent, which will handle the email response, and then we'll end.
Now let's test running it.
In this case you can see the classification decision is just notify and nothing else happens.
Now let's try with an email for which we're expected to respond.
The decision is to respond.
Now to see something interesting.
The initial message is the email.
With this appended respond to this email.
Where did that happen?
Remember that was actually done up in the triage router.
If the triage router makes a decision to respond, all we need to do is update the state of our graph
with an initial message saying respond to this email.
The agent subgraph used that messages key.
So it received then that message from the router and could in turn respond to it.
That's the beauty of using this state object.
It's passed between the nodes of your graph and our router can communicate with our agent very simply through state.
And we can see a call email tool is done and we end.
Now just to bookend this.
Remember we ran land graph dev.
To start a local deployment.
Which allows us to use land graph studio to interact with our agent.
So here's what you'll see when you open studio.
Again, you can just select various agents from your drop down list.
Go to email system.
Here is the graph we actually just built in the notebook.
Now what you can do is open this up and you can see our agent subgraph inside here.
Pass an email.
The router classifies it.
The response agent handles it and we finish.
So this reproduces what we saw in the notebook, but in a nice visual environment.
And you can inspect each step if you'd like.
And the state updates made.
You can see we finally go to done.
And as mentioned before, you can click open run Lang Smith.
And we can now view the trace.
We can see here's our triage router.
This is the triage decision.
You can look at all the prompts used.
And then you can look at the agent itself.
The agent made a tool call to write email.
And then it called the done tool to end.
So now you've seen how to build an agent from scratch.
How to connect it in a workflow to a router.
How to run it.
And how to visualize it in studio.
So now we can build from here to evaluate it.
Add human loop and then finally add memory.